SILVINA VARELA

CONTACT INFO

github.com/silvina-varela linkedin.com/silvinavarela

ABOUT ME

Full Stack Developer with experience building web applications with PERN and MERN stacks. I have 10+ years of experience working with teams and managing projects. I'm resourceful, organized and I have a keen eye for detail that allows me to quickly identify errors.

SKILLS

JavaScript - TypeScript - HTML - CSS

React - Redux

Node - Express - Sequelize

PostgreSQL - MongoDB

Agile Methodologies - Scrum - CI/CD - Git

Figma - Adobe InDesign - Photoshop - Illustrator

Problem solver - fast learner - self-motivated

LANGUAGES

English (C2 Proficient)

Spanish (Native)

Italian (B1 Intermediate)

Portuguese (A1 Basic)

French (A1 Basic)

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Developing Certificate

Henry Bootcamp (2022)

Degree in Editing and Book Publishing

University of Buenos Aires (2012-2016)

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Buenos Aires, Argentina

WEB DEVELOPING EXPERIENCE

FullStack Developer and Team Leader | IFIBYNE (UBA-CONICET), Feb. 2023-now I'm working with an agile team on developing an app for controlling a pipetting robot using ReactJS, NodeJS and MongoDB.

Laravel Developer | CFP, April 2023-now

I'm developing new features for a directory of trade school graduates and integrating a WhatsApp bot.

Frontend Developer | Plan21 Foundation, Dec. 2022-Feb. 2023

Voluteer position. I'm creating a prototype in Figma and developing new features for a web application using React.

E-commerce project, Sept.-Oct. 2022

Worked with an agile team. Managed the GitHub repository and JIRA. Lead the team of frontend developers. Developed features using React.js, MUI and Tailwind.

SPA, Sept. 2022

Developed a SPA using JavaScript, React/Redux, pure CSS, NodeJS, Express, Sequelize and PostgreSQL.

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Copyeditor, Proofreader & Typesetter | 2016-now

Eterna Cadencia Publishing House is a long-term client that has trusted me with many projects (between 1 and 3 a month). I have also worked for other publishing houses and for independent authors.

Freelance Translator (English <> Spanish) | 2016-now

I have translated books, articles and websites.

Senior Book Editor | Biblos Publishing House, Jan. 2016- June 2022

As editor at a Social Sciences and Philosophy publishing house I was responsible for delivering around 5 books on time each month. I oversaw the entire production process. I lead a team of copyeditors and designers. I managed the schedule. I was the main link between the authors and the publishing house. I would occasionally negotiate publishing contracts.

Teaching Assistant | University of Buenos Aires, 2017-2019

Ad honorem position. I assisted the teacher with grading homework and tests. I helped students with activities.

Assistant Book Editor | Eterna Cadencia Publishing House, 2013-2016 I assisted the editor in many tasks, including copyediting, proofreading and typesetting. I was responsible for managing the production of e-books.